

lziping@amazon.com



9793192471



linkedin.com/in/liu

Summary

I'm an engineer. I try to learn a new idea each day; that's because - at least for me, through each new idea learned, I realize a mistaken understanding in a past idea once learned. It's definitely kind of like a research-driven feedback loop, and it's pretty fun.

"Below the surface of the machine, the program moves. Without effort, it expands and contracts. In great harmony, electrons scatter and regroup. The forms on the monitor are but ripples on the water. The essence stays invisibly below."

- Master Yuan-Ma, The Book of Programming

Fair warning, usage of my writing without my permission may result in un-intentional meanings. I always mistakenly leave a logical fallacy in my writing, always driven by way of a disabling form. Quotation with reference to the author is preferred, which allows my own logical fallacies to remain at my disabling fault. I have a life long disability unfortunately.

Experience



SDE 1 of Day 1 - IoT Analytics and Applications

Amazon Web Services (AWS)
May 2021 - Present (1 year +)
IoT Analytics and Applications

Active in ground-breaking empathy-driven research with the internet of things in general and coding really cool stuff.

Working under behm@ to help make operational excellence more empathy driven, through his expertise empathy-driven research led by behm@.

I'm happily also researching cutting edge CW Synthetics and Cypress, along with feature work involved with Frontend. Like, React and stuff.

Working under johnrobw@ as he leads accessible-minded UI designs, through his empathy-driven leadership in UX.

Working under jcrowley@ and his team to artfully write accessible-minded UX text - through his expertise in empathy-led technical writing. Writing is incredibly complex and in-itself more difficult to produce than writing code, so I help jcrowley@ with any technical issues to allow his team to work without the headaches of non-writing related issues.

aws

SDE 1 - IoT Analytics and Applications

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Mar 2020 - Jul 2020 (5 months) IoT Analytics and Applications



Software Engineering Intern

Texas Instruments

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019 (3 months)

Program DSP with FFTs

Programming languages used:

С

The project was not research based like the last one. I also was unable to be a part of the TI Intern Project competition, nor were my peers either. I didn't really have a clear idea of what I was supposed to do, I should have written out a design document but I really didn't know what design was needed. So, I failed the project - and did not communicate nor initiate cross-team collaboration effectively -I empathetically took full responsibility for the failed results of the given project. Zero post-mortem analysis were held, due to my time-frame-boxed internship ending, and I had to go back to school.



Software Engineering Intern

Texas Instruments

May 2018 - Aug 2018 (4 months)

Research involved with real-world application of Speech Recognition based Deep Learning with cutting edge DSPs that handled correlation in similar efficiencies seen in GPUs. Received Full-time Return offer. Very much appreciated my empathy driven key-mentor/manager, and now retired Dr. Lester L. Programming languages used:

С

C++

Java

Python



Patent Engineer Intern

Holland & Hart LLP

May 2017 - Aug 2017 (4 months)

Patent Office Response . Received Return offer.

- Office Actions (arguing through writing why a patent is original through active research in competing cutting edge technologies)

Patent Drafting (a computer did most of it - like as in me using Microsoft Office)

Holland and Hart was amazing. Their in-house software technologies are mind blowing.

I told them I was planning on attending Law School before joining but my career interests changed during the internship due to personal reasons. I decided Medical School seemed better. They fully respected my path-finding driven by personal reasons. The locally seen work environment and culture was truly empathic. Michael truly facilitated a fun and exciting interview for me.

Electrical Engineering Intern

Ticom Geomatics

[©] May 2016 - Aug 2016 (4 months)

Received Return Offer. Declined offer from ARM during this summer to work for Ticom Geomatics instead - I write this because it was an incredibly hard decision to make - so thank you ARM for your given opportunity towards me. I may or may not have worked here. My career interests changed during this time due to seeing a commonly used fossilized organizational structure in some industries due to the inherent wide spectrum of buy-in needed for any new changes and declined returning, they fully respected my career path-finding.

I truly appreciated working with my very supportive and high-empath key-mentor/manager, now a Founder Alvin L.

Researching usage of theoretical to non-theoretical Signal Processing with cutting edge Software Defined Radios (USRP X310 && USRP N210)

Programming Languages Used:

C++

Matlab



undergraduate Research Assistant 🗠 🚾

Cockrell School of Engineering, The University of Texas at Austin

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016 (5 months) Related Fields: Autonomous Robots

I learned how to reverse engineer CMUSphinx through this wonderful research experience and through an empathy driven research key-mentor/manager while working with now Professor, Dr. Baris A

Programming Languages Used:

Python

C++

Software Firmware Engineering Intern

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015 (3 months)

Business Notebook Research and Development . Received Return Offer.

Research in DreamColor calibration in cutting edge laptop display technologies by solving full color spectrum factory calibration with full color spacing by way of automation at the production pipeline floor level.

I declined the return offer after telling them I wanted to work in other industries further forward to determine career path finding routes - they fully respected my ambitious path forward, they as in the two managers I was assigned to. Two managers are better than one - which offered me two perspectives as empathy driven key-mentors/managers, now senior leaders, Mr. Rajesh S. and Mr. Mark G. Mr. Rajesh S. truly facilitated an empathy-driven and fun interview for me. That's the only interview I can remember in vivid detail, after having left a positive mark in my memory.

BIOS/UEFI Embedded Controller HP DreamColor

Programming Languages Used:

C

HP Elitebooks all models with DREAMCOLOR

- Zenbooks
- 850
- 840
- and so much more

Front-End Cashier

Kroger

Jul 2014 - Aug 2014 (2 months)

- Used understanding of the human psyche and irrationality to deal with angry customers.
- Used mathematics and pattern recognition to find change for customers.
- Used memorization and muscle memory to quickly input produce numbers for checkout.
- Promoted from bagger to cashier the day of hiring, due to stand out attitude.
- Gave the customer the item for free when the warehouse inventory staff failed to register the item.
- Helped customers find items. I wasn't too good at that since I'm just a cashier.
- Mistakenly called a manager to override a transaction that was not allowed due to local store policies
- was told it's ok mistakes happen. I replied yes it's ok you made a mistake. Mistakes do happen.

The simple business transaction was reversed - and no study was required, due to a mistaken lack of awareness from my manager since I asked for her help when she was helping another customer. The customers were mistakenly unware and no action was taken.

 Offered the coaching transitional role towards supervisor from Sandra/Sharon S.

I declined the coaching-wellness minded transitional role offer and told them I was going to school. They fully respected my desire for higher education.

Education



The University of Texas at Austin - College of Liberal Arts

Bachelor of Arts (BA), Asian Cultures and Languages

Through studying the BA and granted formally to me from a flagship university, I was able to remove a life long habit of combining the grammar structures of Mandarin Chinese and English - and completely remove the foundational habit of seeing two languages as the same. My writing suffered and moreso my verbal capacity - as I did not truly say what I mean't and my intended meaning was blurred through a crass self developed usage of Chinese Pidgin English. I am so thankful for the liberals arts not only removing my foundational poor habits formed - but providing foundational critical thinking skills - facilitated by a careful awareness of un-intended meanings. Communication is an art, and I will continue to refine my communication skills that which was reformed through a degree of art. Thank you UT - the flagship university, and truly from my heart - infinitely filled now with a love of a world that BE a one world referred in a motto form: "What starts here changes [our] world."

Brazosport College



Clute. Texas



Cockrell School of Engineering, The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Science/Engineering - BE, Electrical Engineering Focus was on everything related to the (ALU) Arithmetic Logic Unit

Met with Dr. Veronica V, Director, who truly gave me strength to BE vocal about my concerns.

Met with a former Chair Dr. Ahmed T who transcended his role to provide mentor-ship to me as a regressed student. Met with a former dean Dr. Sharon W, and I felt heard with true empathy with my concerns. I may have graduated with a degree - may but not limited to not. I found reconciliation by way of empathy leading professors who told me that it isn't some degree that is required to allow anyone to pioneer new paths anywhere. I felt heard from un-seen professors now seen - who led their classes with empathy. I'm grateful for the engineering professors who told me no degree makes anyone become who - and to value any and/or no degrees. And for that reason, I do definitely state that I graduated with a research driven non-degree instead. So, my internships are true degrees, along with my Non-Degree Empathy-Led Research-Driven diploma from a college, stated in diploma form as BS.

Skills

Writing • Java • C Language • JavaScript • Engineering • Signal Processing • Algorithms • Microcontrollers • Mathematics • Empathy

Honors & Awards



5A Honor Band - Texas Music Educators Assn

Part of the 5A Honor band which placed number one out of all 5A High School symphonic bands in Texas. Played lead Alto Saxophone. Listen Here: https://play.spotify.com/album/2TNqwGUNosCGC2cRgg7bQB

Minor Hypothesis: Due to the staging and a lack of temperature control from a supposed worldclass stage, our instruments lacked a constant environment to remain in tune.



Eagle Scout - Scouts BSA

Troop 328
Bay Area Council

(FORMER ISSUER Boy Scouts of America)
Current Issuer: Scouts BSA - "Scout me in!"

Eagle project consisted of building parking bollards for local bird sanctuary. Ziping supervised with empathy - a group of scouts in the construction of the project - which involved managing concrete mixing, post hole digging, and installation of bollards among different teams. Recipient of the Lowe's National Eagle Scout Project Impact Grant. Ziping Liu wants to also note that he received donated rental equipment from The Home Depot - *minute hypothesis: Lowe's didn't like that.*



Homecoming King - Brazoswood High School

Created and led a campaign to not win the Homecoming King just to mistakenly upset the varsity football team.

Ziping Liu still won the Homecoming King. Hypothesis: the varsity football team lacked trust from the student body due to constant mistaken business critical decisions within their projects; as a result, many projects unfortunately failed to meet the expectations of the student body. Historical data analysis highlights a semi-final round achieving varsity football team four years ago - resulting in a higher than normal expectation from the student body.

GT

Graduate Admissions Offer - Masters in CS - Georgia Institute of Technology

Sep 2021

No scholarship received, admissions acceptance declined with full honors by Ziping Liu.

Resume is accurate as of April 11, 2022 through the best ability of Ziping Liu and his understanding at the time stated.

Ziping Liu, April 11, 2022